

☑ DruSerkes@gmail.com ② druserkes 🦶 203-912-2047 🤉 New York, NY in dru-serkes 🗘 druserkes

SUMMARY

Full stack software engineer with a passion for clean code and DRY principles. Specialties include React, Javascript + Typescript, ES6. Currently owning the SDLC for a codebase on a remote, empathetic, client-focused team. Former professional Broadway actor of over 10 years.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Typescript, Javascript, NodeJS, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL

LIBRARIES AND FRAMEWORKS: React, Redux, Express, Flask, jQuery, Jest, React Testing Library, Bootstrap, Material UI

TOOLS: AWS, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, MongoDB, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Netlify, Jira, VS Code

SOFT SKILLS: Public Speaking, Remote Collaboration, Attention to detail, Listening

EXPERIENCE

Zephyrx November 2021 - Current

Software Engineer · Remote

- Oversaw Typescript refactor of React Javascript codebase, leading to improved product stability
- . Constructed real-time video interface with AWS Kinesis and WebRTC, expanding clinical access to and usage of our real-time coaching feature
- Led a team that rapidly iterated on bespoke client solutions, promoting pair programming and code review, resulting in smoother release cycles
- Formalized dev and release processes by writing extensive documentation, leading to concise version histories and reduced meetings
- · Regularly met with clients to understand users, collect requirements, spec requests, and set development roadmap

May 2021 - November 2021

Associate Software Engineer · Remote

- · Assisted in implementation of real-time video and messaging via Amazon Chime, facilitating use of our dashboard for remote appointments
- Improved data flow by leveraging React-Redux to refactor state management, resulting in reduced page load times
- Leveraged our Serverless AWS API to build out admin tools, significantly reducing development team support workload

November 2020 - May 2021

Technical Engineer, Jr. · Remote

- Added accessibility for 20+ new languages, resulting in international use of our provider dashboard
- Supported QA team by developing a unit test suite and documentation, contributing to a single communication close rate over 75%
- Ensured production stability by coordinating testing of web and mobile components, improving team understanding of product

Various Employers June 2009 - March 2020

Actor

• Collaborated on over 2,300 live performances from New York to Las Vegas in ubiquitous Broadway shows (e.g Jersey Boys, Rock of Ages)

PROJECTS

Lyrify

Lyrics for Spotify listeners

- Crafted a responsive SPA with React, Redux, and Material UI components working with a Node | Express backend
- Followed Oauth2 protocol for login via Spotify and consumed multiple 3rd party APIs for data aggregation with PostgreSQL

The Easy Meal

Discover recipes, construct and email yourself a grocery list

- Built Flask | Python backend serving dynamic Jinja HTML templates, and a UI responsively styled with Bootstrap and custom CSS
- Consumed 3rd party API to access over 380,000 recipes, and cached recipe data with PostgreSQL to reduce API calls.

Jobly

Mock job-seeking website

- Developed a RESTful API with Node | Express, and a modular UI for this React SPA
- Implemented auth, following JWT standard

EDUCATION

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track Certification 2020 700+ hour full stack immersive in Javascript, Python, and more Emerson College BFA Musical Theatre 2011 Cum Laude. Dean Scholarship Recipient

VOLUNTEERING

Artists Who Code · Member

Advocate for creative professionals with non-traditional backgrounds in the tech industry